DANILA RASSOKHIN

Yerevan, Armenia (ready to relocate)

danilarassokhin@gmail.com • Telegram: @RassokhinD • https://linkedin.com/in/danilarassokhin

SUMMARY

Java/Kotlin developer with three years of experience building and maintaining applications using Spring Boot, Hibernate, and related technologies. I have improved application performance and reduced errors, and I've helped make development processes more efficient. I share my knowledge through mentoring, technical interviews, writing about Java, Spring, and Postgres on Medium, and by creating a free Prolog programming course. I'm looking for a challenging Java Engineer role where I can use my skills to work on important projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

YLAB

Middle Java/Kotlin Developer

Aug 2023 - Present

- Optimized the image generation process, resulting in a 20% reduction in RAM usage, leading to improved application stability and reduced server costs
- Implemented image compression using ImageIO, preserving original resolution; This resulted in a 30% reduction of S3 bucket size and lower storage costs
- Replaced Jasper Reports with Apache POI for Excel report generation, resulting in a 10% increase in report generation speed
- Introduced Camunda BPMN scheme testing, reducing runtime bugs by 60%
- Developed Kotlin-based testing utilities with a user-friendly DSL for Camunda, increasing test writing speed by 15% and boosting team's velocity by 5%
- Achieved 100% test coverage for two large BPMN schemes, comprising over 700 elements and 1100 flows
- Designed user-friendly utilities and 3 load testing scenarios using JavaScript and K6
- Enhanced team efficiency through a new practice, resulting in 2-3 additional closed business tasks per sprint
- Performed code reviews for over 100 interns in an internal Java course and more than 20 interviews

YLAB

Junior Java Developer

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Covered 7 BPMN processes for Camunda with integration tests, resulting in improved stability
- Achieved test coverage of 97% for 15 Spring microservices using unit tests and integration tests

YLAB

Junior Java Developer

SEP 2022 - May 2023

- Designed and developed a BPMN migration tool, similar to Liquibase, that accelerated development by 10%
- Created a REST connector for Camunda 8 for distributed logging and reduced error investigation time by 10%
- Created a job worker for Camunda 8 to enable uploading and downloading files from S3 within BPMN tasks
- Redesigned the search functionality over Elasticsearch to support displaying over 10,000 documents

EDUCATION

KUBAN STATE UNIVERSITY

Krasnodar, Russia

Master of Informatics And Applied Mathematics

2022-2024

Studied computer science. Participated in several conferences and authored papers on cryptography and bioinformatics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Java, Kotlin
- Frameworks: Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JOOQ, Camunda, gRPC
- Databases and platforms: Postgres, Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch, Redis
- Tools: Docker, CI/CD, Apache Avro
- System design: Microservices, REST API, Gateway, Reactive
- Languages: Russian (native), English (B2)